<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><annuaire>	<code>		<category>Airliner Internal Codes</category>		<number>01</number>		<content><![CDATA[DELAYS FOR TECHNICAL REASONS OF OTHER AIRCRAFTS THAN THOSE OF THY A.O. (TURKISH AIRLINES, INC.)<br><br>A: Delays for technical reasons of other aircrafts than those of THY INC.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airliner Internal Codes</category>		<number>02</number>		<content><![CDATA[DUE TO THE PROCEDURE OF THE APU INOP AIRCRAFT’S STARTING ENGINES AT THE PARKING POSITION OR THE AIRCRAFT’S STARTING ENGINES AT THE PARKING POSITION AND INITIATING THE MOVEMENT BY ITS OWN POWER<br><br>A: Aircraft’s starting engines before the push back due to the unserviceable condition of APU<br><i>Applicable for the delay occurring in the cases, where the Aircraft needs to start the engines before the push back due to the unserviceable condition of APU. (All doors should have been closed and the tower should have authorized the starting of engines. The unserviceable condition of APU should be beforehand known, and GPU-ASU should be ready beforehand by the aircraft. Code 39 shall be used for the delays occurring due to the standby for the said.)</i><br><br>B: Aircraft’s starting movement at the parking position by its own power.<br><i>Applicable for the delays occurring due to the time elapsing for the starting of the engine in the cases, where the aircraft needs to move at the parking position by its own power. (All doors should have been closed and the tower should have authorized the starting of engines.)</i>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airliner Internal Codes</category>		<number>03</number>		<content><![CDATA[AUDIT<br><br>A: Internal audit<br><br>B: External audit<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airliner Internal Codes</category>		<number>04</number>		<content><![CDATA[DELAYS UNDER ONGOING EXAMINATION<br><br>A: Delays under ongoing examination<br><i>In the cases where the applicable reason of delay has not been identified, the MVT Message shall be promptly sent with this delay code. The delay code should be revised by the related station and/or GOC once the actual reason is identified (within 24 hours at latest from the take-off).</i>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airliner Internal Codes</category>		<number>05</number>		<content><![CDATA[STANDARD DELAY CODE FOR ACARS-ORIGINATED AUTOMATED DEPARTURE MESSAGE<br><i>The delay code identifier applicable for the cases, where the MTV Message is sent automatically by the system by the employment of the ACARS times. The applicable delay code should be allocated as the MVT Message is sent by the station.</i>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Others</category>		<number>06</number>		<content><![CDATA[NO GATES/STANDS AVAILABLE DUE TO OWN AIRLINE ACTIVITIES<br><br>A: No gates/stands available due to own airline activities]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Schedules</category>		<number>09</number>		<content><![CDATA[THE SCHEDULED GROUND TIME LESS THAN DECLARED MINIMUM GROUND TIME<br><br>A: Technical<br><b>Responsible SCHD</b><br><br>B: Commercial<br><b>Responsible SCHD</b><br><br>C: Planned<br><b>Responsible SCHD</b><br><br>X: Slot(CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>11</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE CHECK-IN (ACCEPTANCE AFTER DEADLINE)<br><br>A: Late check-in of transfer passengers<br><i>Late check-in conducted in spite of sufficient transfer time</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Waiting list process<br><i>Stand-by passengers acceptance etc. </i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Late acceptance of passengers with confirmed reservation<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Group check-in <br><i>Late arrival of the group for check-in</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Delays in transportation/ access to the airport (closure, accumulation, accident etc.)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>N: Due to the collection of excess baggage fees<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>O: Passenger re-route process due to the cancellation of flight<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>P: Late check-in due to e-ticket problems<br><b>Responsible  GOPS</b><br><br>Q: Due to the staff<br><i>Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc.<br>11D shall be applicable in the cases of inadequate number of staff</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>12</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE CHECK-IN (CONGESTION IN CHECK-IN AREA)<br><br>A: Congestion in check-in area<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Congestion in transfer area<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Group check-in<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Delays in transportation/access to the airport (closure, accumulation, accident etc.)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>F: Waiting list process<br><i>Stand-by passengers acceptance etc.</i><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Due to the staff<br><i>Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc. 12B shall be applicable in the cases of inadequate number of staff.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>13</number>		<content><![CDATA[CHECK-IN ERROR (PASSENGERS AND BAGGAGE)<br><br>A: Check-in error at the station <br><i>This code shall apply for the K-edit access interruptions, APIS details, special cargo information and the related detail entries.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>J: Intermodal check-in error (vessel, train etc.)<br><i>Any error that occurs during the check-in at other locations that the terminal</i><br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>K: Double seating/double check-in <br><i>Such as repeated check-in.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>L: Documentation error (ticket/visa/passport etc.)<br><i>Receipt of false or invalid coupon, admission of passengers without a valid passport and visa, including the medical reports of sick passengers.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>M: Editing error <br><i>Applicable to the delays that occur as a consequence of the failure to enter the details, which should be entered to the system, at the flight preparation stage. Oxygen bottle, stretcher, crew rest seat, babies, group passengers etc.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: E-ticket check-in error<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>14</number>		<content><![CDATA[OVERSALES (BOOKING ERRORS)<br><br>A: Over sales<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>B: Booking error<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>N: Seat/curtain arrangements due to cabin configuration change<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>O: Passengers who are denied boarding due to overbooking<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>P: Accomodating of passengers from another oversold flight.<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>Q: Problems related to involuntary upgrading– downgrading of passengers<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>R: Erroneous reservation of passengers in need of special care (AVIH, WCHR, stretcher request etc.)<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>S: E-ticket reservation errors<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>T: Reservation errors by agencies<br><b>Responsible RESE</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>15</number>		<content><![CDATA[BOARDING (DISCREPANCIES AND PAGING, MISSING CHECKED-IN PASSENGERS)<br><br>A: Boarding error/incompatibility of passenger figures <br><i>Admission of the passengers of other flight</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Late boarding<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Slow boarding<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Missing/late checked-in passenger <br><i>Waiting for the passenger without baggage under the instructions of the station manager. This code shall be applicable in the event the passenger applies to gate during baggage assortment and admission thereof under the instructions of the station manager. 32R shall apply in the event the passenger does not apply but the baggage fail to be assorted in due time, and 85B shall apply in the event the baggage are assorted in due time yet delay occurs nonetheless.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Late bus order to boarding gate<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Documentation (ticket/visa/passport etc.)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>G: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>I: Excess hand baggage handling during the boarding. (collection, loading, issuing excess ticket)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>O: Late/erroneous warning of the baggage assortment detail to the reconciliation <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases where the said details are communicated upon the expiration of the specified boarding time.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>Q: Loading of unidentified baggage upon the announcement of the respective passenger<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>R: Direction of passenger to the wrong parking position/wrong gate<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>S: Due to the staff Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc. 15G shall be applicable in the cases of inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>U: Assignment of new seat numbers to and placement of passengers due to the modification of aircraft’s configuration or type <br><i>This code shall apply in the event of the modification of the seat numbers due to the change of the type or the configuration of aircraft less then two hours before the departure. In the cases where the seat numbers are modified more than two hours before the flight, it shall be considered that there is adequate time, and 15A shall apply.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>16</number>		<content><![CDATA[COMMERCIAL PUBLICITY / PASSENGER CONVENIENCE, VIP (PRESS, GROUND MEALS AND MISSING PERSONAL ITEMS)<br><br>A: VIP boarding<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>B: Handling of unruly passengers<br><i>Unruly passengers</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>D: Missing personal effects<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>E: DEPO/INAD passenger handling<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>F: The catering offered to the passenger on the ground due to interruption<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>G: Passenger deplaning voluntarily <br><i>Applicable only for passengers without baggage. 85B shall apply for the passengers with baggage.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>H: Illness/death of passenger on board <br><i>Including the deplaning of the passenger and the baggage thereof and waiting for the airport authority.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>N: Activities on board of the press organs<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>S: Admission of passengers without commercial conjunction from another airliner<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br><b>Uncontrolled</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>17</number>		<content><![CDATA[CATERING ORDER (LATE OR INCORRECT ORDER GIVEN TO SUPPLIER)<br>A: Late catering order<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Wrong catering order<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>P: Late order of addition to the return catering by out-station.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>Q: Change in catering due to delay (change from breakfast to lunch etc.)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>18</number>		<content><![CDATA[BAGGAGE PROCESSING (SORTING ETC.)<br>87V SHALL APPLY FOR SORTER PROBLEMS<br><br>A: Late Delivery of hold baggage<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Baggage reconciliation and assortment problems <br><i>Applicable in the cases of inadequate number of baggage reading staff, wrong/late/slow baggage reading/ notification.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Shipment of baggage upon the attachment of rush label (including the baggage from other flights)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>O: Shipment of rush baggage from other airliners<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>Q: İnsufficient baggage reconciliation equipment<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>R: Shipment of the baggage to the wrong aircraft<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>S: Errors of the baggage reconciliation coordination office<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Passenger and Baggage</category>		<number>19</number>		<content><![CDATA[REDUCED MOBILITY (BOARDING, DEBOARDING OF PASSENGERS WITH REDUCED MOBILITY)<br><i>THE PASSENGERS WITH REDUCED MOBILITY DUE TO OLD AGE ARE ALSO INCLUDED TO THE SCOPE OF PASSENGERS WITH REDUCED MOBILITY.</i><br><br>A: Boarding of passengers with reduced mobility<br><i>19C shall apply in the cases where the delay originates from the handling contractor. This code may also apply for such flights as pilgrimage – umrah flights, by which numerous passengers with reduced mobility due to old age.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>B: Deplaning of passengers with reduced mobility <br><i>19C shall apply in the cases where the delay originates from the handling performer. This code may also apply for such flights as pilgrimage – umrah flights, by which numerous passengers with reduced mobility due to old age.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>C: Delays originating from the handling contractor performing carriage of wchr, stchr passengers<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>21</number>		<content><![CDATA[DOCUMENTATION (ERRORS ETC.)<br><br>A: Late cargo figure <br><i>Applicable to the delays occurring due to the late delivery of cargo figure.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Wrong cargo figure <br><i>Applicable to the delays occurring due to errors with or changes to the cargo figure delivered.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Late cargo documentation (NOTOC, customs documents, CGO manifest).<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Wrong cargo documents<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>22</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE POSITIONING<br><br>A: Re-loading due to missing cargo.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Inadequacy/lacking of cargo equipment (tractor, cargo carrier etc.).<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Moving to the wrong parking position or moving to the parking position with missing cargo or failure to move to the parking position <br><i>This code shall apply to the cases originating from personnel’s failure even though the entire documentation is accurate.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>N: Late provision of loading materials <br><i>Applicable in the cases of late arrival or non-arrival of the materials necessary for the loads from the cargo (load spreaders, tie-down materials etc.).</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>O: Due to the staff <br><i>22B shall apply in the cases of late arrival to work, leaving work before ending of working hours, inadequate number of staff etc.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>23</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE ACCEPTANCE<br><br>A: Late acceptance of cargo – commercial reasons.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Stand-by cargo acceptance.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Express cargo (VIC etc.).<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>E: Diplomatic mail.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>24</number>		<content><![CDATA[INADEQUATE PACKAGING<br><br>A: Load shifting in the cargo shipped to the aircraft<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Dangerous Goods.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Wrong pallet preparation.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>N: Late loading due to contour overlapped/rebuilding of ULD<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>25</number>		<content><![CDATA[OVERSALES (BOOKING ERRORS)<br><br>A: Over sales.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Reservation/booking errors <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases of cargo acceptance not in conformity to the aircraft limits. (RRY, AVI, HUM, HEA, etc.).</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Stand-by cargo acceptance.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Cargo and Mail</category>		<number>26</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE PREPARATION IN WAREHOUSE<br><br>A: Pallet preparation errors.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Contours (disfigured, overlapped pallets).<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>E: Warehouse congestion.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Mail Only</category>		<number>27</number>		<content><![CDATA[DOCUMENTATION, PACKAGING ETC.<br><br>A: Late mail figures.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Wrong mail figures.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Late documentation.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Inaccurate documentation.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Mail Only</category>		<number>28</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE POSITIONING<br><br>A: Re-loading due to missing mail.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>B: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>C: Inadequacy/lacking of equipment (tractor, cargo carrier etc.).<br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>D: Moving to the wrong parking position or moving to the parking position with missing cargo or failure to move to the parking position<br><i>This code shall apply to the cases originating from staff failure even though the entire documentation is accurate.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>N: Due to the personnel <br><i>Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc. 28B shall be applicable in the cases of inadequate number of staff.</i><br><b>Responsible CRGO</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Mail Only</category>		<number>29</number>		<content><![CDATA[CA Late acceptance (mail only)]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>31</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRCRAFT DOCUMENTATION LATE/INACCURATE (WEIGHT AND BALANCE, GENERAL DECLARATION, PAX MANIFEST ETC.)<br><br>A: Late documentation.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Inaccurate documentation.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Late "LOAD AND TRIM SHEET".<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Inaccurate "LOAD AND TRIM SHEET".<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Repositioning of passengers/ cargo due to trim-out.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Inaccurate data on DCS System (layout plan, hold version etc.).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>G: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>H: Load plan errors.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>I: Late fuel figures <br><i>Late communication by the operation coordinator at aircraft of the fuel figure to the personnel preparing the LOAD AND TRIM SHEET.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Document renewal due to last minute changes <br><i>Applicable in the cases of any changes to the balance, load plan, passenger manifest, NOTOC etc. (which do not arise from any errors).</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>O: Due to the staff <br><i>Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc. 31G shall be applicable in the cases of inadequate number of staff.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>S: Late delivery of flight documents to Cokpit (flight plan, customs documents) <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases where the documents are received timely from the related units and are delivered to the pilot-in-command with delay.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>P: Other errors originating from the operation coordinator at aircraft <br><i>Applicable for the errors by both the sending and the welcoming coordinators.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>32</number>		<content><![CDATA[LOADING/ UNLOADING (BULKY, SPECIAL LOAD, CABIN LOAD, LACK OF LOADING STAFF)<br><br>A: Cabin loading, dry cargo, oversize cargo, unformed cargo, special cargo (HEA, PER, RRY, AVIH etc.).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Late loading <br><i>Also applicable to the late loading problems with cargo aircrafts.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Improper loading (not in compliance with the load plan or the loading principles).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: ULD damage <br><i>Applicable to the delays occurring as a consequence of the damages during loading/unloading. Otherwise, 38B shall apply.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Failure of onboard loading systems <br><i>Applicable to the loading problems causing delays due to the previously known loading system failures on aircrafts with ULD loading. 41D shall apply in the cases where such system failures render the loading impracticable and the technical failure should essentially be eliminated. Code 42 shall apply in the cases occurring due to damage.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>G: Late provision of loading materials <br><i>Applicable to late arrival/ lack of the ropes or the other ancillary loading materials for the special baggage arriving along with the passengers.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>M: Late unloading <br><i>Also applicable to the late unloading problems with cargo aircrafts.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Due to the staff <br><i>Late arrival at work, leaving work before the ending of working hours etc. 32C shall be applicable in<br>the cases of inadequate number of staff.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>R: Inaccurate or extremely long lasting of missing passenger baggage assortment <br><i>Applicable to the cases, where the staff actually loading onboard sorts the wrong baggage or sorts the baggage in extremely long period of time.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>S: Loading alteration due to last minute changes (not originating from an error).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>33</number>		<content><![CDATA[LOADING EQUIPMENT (LACK OF OR BREAKDOWN; E.G. CONTAINER PALLET LOADER, LACK OF STAFF)<br><br>A: Late equipment (forklift, tractor, high-loader, conveyor etc.).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Lack of equipment.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Lack of equipment operators.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Unserviceable equipment.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Inaccurate equipment.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>34</number>		<content><![CDATA[SERVICING EQUIPMENT (LACK OF OR BREAKDOWN, LACK OF STAFF, E.G. STEPS)<br><br>A: Absence/late arrival of boarding bridge operator <br><i>This code shall apply to the delays due to the late arrival of the operator without regards to the service being provided either by the handling performer or the airport operator. (Code 87T shall apply in the cases of boarding bridge failure.).</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS/ARPT</b><br><br>B: Lack/late arrival/unserviceable condition of air stairs.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Lack/late arrival/unserviceable condition of bus/midibus.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Lack/late arrival/unserviceable condition of portable water service vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Lack/late arrival/unserviceable condition of toilet service vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Lack/late arrival/unserviceable condition of operation vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>O: Lack or absence/ late arrival of ambulance or operator, unserviceable condition of vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>35</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRCRAFT CLEANING<br><br>A: Late completion of cleaning.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Insufficient/inaccurate cleaning equipment.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Equipment failure Garbage truck, vacuum cleaner etc.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Crew being recalled due to incomplete conduct of cleaning.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Additional or special cleaning requests <br><i>Code 68D shall apply in the event such requests are submitted specially by the cabin crew.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>G: Cleaning of the cockpit’s windshield.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>H: Short or late delivery of the cabin materials/items brought by the cleaning personnel (e.g. Blankets, earphones, pillows).<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>W: Additional cleaning due to weather conditions <br><i>This code shall apply in such cases as the accumulation of rainwater at the front galley, and failure to collect the catering due to weather conditions on board of a coming aircraft.</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>36</number>		<content><![CDATA[FUELLING/DEFUELLING (FUEL SUPPLIER)<br><br>A: Lack of fuel truck.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>B: Late arrival of fuel truck.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>C: Fuel truck failure during operation.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>D: Late defuelling <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases where the defuelling is completed in a longer period of time than planned due to a reason originating from the equipment of the fuel supplier. Code 96N shall apply in the event of the need for defuelling since the aircraft has been changed due to operational necessities, and Code 46N shall apply in the event of the need for defuelling since the aircraft has been changed for technical failure.</i><br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>E: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>F: Fuelling error.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>G: Implementation of special procedure due to technical reasons <br><i>Applicable only for previously known situations; while Code 41A shall apply for the technical problems arising during the operation.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>H: Fuel hydrant system <br><i>This code shall apply in the case of failure with the equipment used by the fuel supplier. Code 87J shall apply in the cases of general failures.</i><br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>I: Lack of fuel quality/contaminated fuel<br><i>This code shall apply in the cases where the flight stands by for the new fuel due to the mentioned case.</i><br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>J: Fuel spill.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>K: Unable to fuelling due to the improper parking of aircraft.<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>37</number>		<content><![CDATA[CATERING (LATE DELIVERY OR LOADING)<br><br>C: Catering equipment failure.<br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><br>D: Late arrival of catering.<br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><br>E: Inaccurate or inadequate catering loading (including the catering materials; e.g. cassettes, newspapers, relax set, amenity kit etc.) <br><i>Passenger and crew catering.</i><br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><br>G: Failure in loading the return flight catering at the previous station <br><i>This code shall apply for the stations, at which we cannot provide catering service. Applicable in the cases, where the catering supplies fail to be loaded despite the timely notification of the catering order.</i><br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><br>S: The ground time of the aircraft being shorter than the catering loading time as per the catering contract.<br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>R: Change of catering loading due to aircraft change <br><i>Code 37D shall apply in the event the aircraft change occurs three hours in advance for wide-body aircrafts and two hours in advance for narrow-body aircrafts.</i><br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>X: Slot missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>38</number>		<content><![CDATA[ULD (LACK OF OR SERVICEABILITY) <br><i>THIS CODE SHALL APPLY IN THE CASES OF THE INTERRUPTIONS TO ARISE IF UDL PLANNING IS PROPER.</i><br><br>A: Inadequate number of ULDs.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Damaged or unserviceable ULD <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases where the ULD is damaged but should essentially be used.<br></i><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>C: Late ULD supply to handling unit.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X :Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Aircraft and Ramp Handling</category>		<number>39</number>		<content><![CDATA[TECHNICAL EQUIPMENT (LACK OF OR BREAKDOWN, LACK OF STAFF; E.G. PUSH-BACK)<br><br>A: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of GPU.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of de-icing vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of tow bar.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Lack/ breakdown/late arrival of air starter.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of air conditioner.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of push back vehicle.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>G: Inadequate number of staff.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>H: Lack/breakdown/late arrival of other technical equipment.<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>41</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRCRAFT DEFECTS<br><br>A: Technical defects <br><i>Codes 51, 52 shall apply for aircraft damages.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Cabin equipment defects (e.g. seats, galley etc.) <br><i>This code shall apply in the cases of the breakdown of baby harnesses, baby trolleys.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>C: In-flight entertainment equipment defects<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>D: Aircraft loading system failure <br><i>The Code 52 shall apply for the delays occurring as a consequence of any damages during the loading. Code 32F shall apply if the unserviceable condition of the system is known. 41D shall apply in the case of other failures.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>E: Awaiting Departure equipment <br><i>Applicable in the cases of tool and equipment standby. (including nets)</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>N: Awaiting Cabin – cockpit maintenance logbook<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>O: Stand-by for MEL or CDL approval (go to) <br><i>Applicable in the cases of excessive number of items included into MEL or of the need for longer period of time for MEL examination.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>P: Change of the status of MEL (from go-to to no-go) <br><i>MEL status becoming or transforming into no-go.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>Q: Inadequate number of staff <br><i>Such cases as standby for line maintenance mechanic to the aircraft.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>R: Defective status/refilling of emergency equipment <br><i>Such as oxygen bottles, fire extinguishers. (except for the cases of essential need of passengers to use the medical supplies (oxygen bottle, DR. KIT, FAK e.g.) during the flights)</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>S: Missing technical documentation <br><i>Applicable only to such cases, where the technical breakdown documentation goes missing.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>T: Late reporting of technical defect by the mechanic.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>42</number>		<content><![CDATA[SCHEDULED MAINTENANCE (LATE RELEASE)<br><br>A: Late documentation <br><i>Applicable also to such cases, where the technical documentation goes missing. Code 61H shall apply in the event the technical documentation of the flight on line goes missing.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Late delivery from maintenance <br><i>The aircraft shall be considered not lately delivered if it is released for flight MGT+20 minutes (towing time) before the flight. In the event the towing operation lasts longer than 20 minutes, code 39F shall apply for the delays due to lack of push back, and code 89K shall apply to the cases, where the push back is ready and ATC’s permission is expected.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>N: Inadequate maintenance slots <br><i>Applicable to the cases, where the aircraft arrives lately for maintenance, and the time allotted for maintenance (ground time) is inadequate.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>P: Late documentation (Third party maintenance) <br><i>Applicable to the maintenances performed by other performers than Turkish Airlines Inc.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>R: Late delivery from maintenance (Third party maintenance) <br><i>Applicable to the maintenances performed by other performers than Turkish Airlines Inc.. The aircraft shall be considered not lately delivered if it is released for flight MGT+20 minutes (towing time) before the flight. In the event the towing operation lasts longer than 20 minutes, code 39F shall apply for the delays due to lack of push back, and code 89K shall apply to the cases, where the push back is ready and ATC’s permission is expected.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>43</number>		<content><![CDATA[NON-SCHEDULED MAINTENANCE (SPECIAL CHECKS AND/OR ADDITIONAL WORKS BEYOND NORMAL MAINTENANCE SCHEDULE)<br><br>A: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Late documentation <br><i>Applicable also to such cases, where the technical documentation goes missing.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>C: Non-scheduled special maintenance <br><i>Applicable also to weekly/daily layover, special maintenances and checks.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>N: Late check-in on ground.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>P: Wheel and tire assy/break unit replacement <br><i>Code 51H shall apply to the replacements due to FOD.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>44</number>		<content><![CDATA[SPARES AND MAINTENANCE EQUIPMENT (LACK OF OR BREAKDOWN)<br><br>A: Lack of spare parts.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Lack or breakdown of maintenance equipment<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>C: Late delivery of spare parts (late procurement from the warehouse) <br><i>Code 87 shall apply to the cases, where the late delivery is caused not by technical reasons by the airport facilities.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>N: Lack of furnishings (seat covers, curtains etc.).<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>Q: The part from the warehouse being incompatible<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>45</number>		<content><![CDATA[AOG SPARES (TO BE CARRIED TO ANOTHER STATION)<br><br>A: Late dispatch to/arrival at the aircraft of spare parts <br><i>Applicable in the cases, where the AOG is dispatched to or arrives at the aircraft lately.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Late/inaccurate arrival of AOG spares documentation <br><i>Serviceable component card, airwaybill etc. for AOG spares.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>D: Loading of the spares to the aircraft/ re-loading to the aircraft <br><i>Applicable to the cases, where the loading of the aircraft is changed due to AOG.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>F: AOG for third parties.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>N: Dispatching of technical staff to the station, where the no go aircraft is located.<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>46</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRCRAFT CHANGE (FOR TECHNICAL REASONS)<br><br>A: Collisions at Apron, change of aircraft due to damage.<br><i>Code 51N shall apply.</i><br><br>B: Change of aircraft due to the damages that occur during the flight.<br><i>Code 52N shall apply.</i><br><br>E: Change of aircraft due to late delivery from maintenance<br><br>N: Change of aircraft due to technical defect.<br><i>One of the codes 46, 51 or 52 shall apply as appropriate solely for the first delay, and code 96S shall apply for all other changes that ocur on the same day. (one day before is inclusive for extended range flights).</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>47</number>		<content><![CDATA[STAND-BY AIRCRAFT (LACK OF PLANNED STAND-BY AIRCRAFT FOR TECHNICAL REASONS)<br><br>A: Stand-by aircraft (lack of planned stand-by aircraft for technical reasons).<br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Technical and Aircraft Equipment</category>		<number>48</number>		<content><![CDATA[SCHEDULED CABIN CONFIGURATION/VERSION ADJUSTMENT<br><br>A: Cabin divider/seat adjustment (c/cl curtain and seat adjustment) <br><i>Applicable to the delays that occur in spite of timely notification.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>B: Stretcher installation <br><i>Applicable to the delays that occur in spite of timely notification.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>C: Medical equipment <br><i>Applicable to the delays that occur in spite of timely notification.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>D: Crew rest seating <br><i>Applicable to the delays that occur in spite of timely notification.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Damage to Aircraft</category>		<number>51</number>		<content><![CDATA[DAMAGE DURING FLIGHT OPERATIONS (BIRD OR LIGHTNING STRIKE, TURBULENCE, HEAVY OR OVERWEIGHT LANDING, COLLISIONS DURING TAXIING)<br><br>A: Lightning strike<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>B: Bird strike<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>C: Other damages during flight operations (including cargo and baggage damages)<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>D: Due to severe weather conditions<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>E: Overweight/Heavy Landing<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>F: Collision during taxiing<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>G: Aircraft veer off the runway or taxiway<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>H: FOD damage<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>J: Damaging of aircraft by the passengers (including the blockage of toilets and lavatory)<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>K: Cooling of aircraft’s brakes<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>N: Change of aircraft due to damage in the air.<br><i>Applicable to the cases of change of aircraft when the aircraft becomes no-go. (including the awaiting until the arrival of the new aircraft)</i><br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Damage to Aircraft</category>		<number>52</number>		<content><![CDATA[DAMAGE DURING GROUND OPERATIONS, (COLLISIONS (OTHER THAN DURING TAXIING), LOADING/OFF-LOADING DAMAGE, CONTAMINATION, TOWING, EXTREME WEATHER CONDITIONS)<br><br>A: Collision during towing (other than taxiing)<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>B: Damage due to severe weather conditions<br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>C: Damage by loading equipment<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Damage by boarding bridge<br><b>Responsible GOPS/ARPT</b><br><br>E: Damage by mobile stairs<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>F: Damage by fuelling equipment<br><b>Responsible FUEL</b><br><br>G: Damage by technical support equipment<br><b>Responsible GOPS/TECH</b><br><br>H: Damage by catering equipment<br><b>Responsible CTRG</b><br><br>I: Damage by cleaning equipment<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>J: Damage by push-back equipment<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>K: Accidental deployment of escape slide (dropping, deployment).<br><i>Code 68E shall apply in the cases where it occurs due to cabin crew’s fault.</i><br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>N: Damage by technical personnel.<br><i>The applicable sub code shall be used in the event it occurs during technical maintenance inside the hangar.</i><br><b>Responsible TECH</b><br><br>O: Damage by the operational personnel<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>P: Change of aircraft due to damage on the ground.<br><i>This code shall apply to the delays occurring during the rectification of the damage or the delays, which occur due to the damages that necessitate the change of aircraft due to the aircraft becoming no-go (including the delays due to the awaiting of the new aircraft).</i><br><b>Responsible DMGE</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>EDP/Automated Equipment Failure</category>		<number>55</number>		<content><![CDATA[DEPARTURE CONTROL<br><br>A: Local DCS equipment failure (except for TROYA)<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>B: DCS host failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>C: Host network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>D: Local network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>E: Self service equipment failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>N: Traffic system failure (check-in, boarding, APIS e.g.)<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>O: Operations system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>P: Baggage reconciliation system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>S: Netline-Ops/UHM system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>T: Ticket sales/reservation system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>U: Communications system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>EDP/Automated Equipment Failure</category>		<number>56</number>		<content><![CDATA[CARGO PREPARATION/ DOCUMENTATION<br><br>A: Local equipment failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>B: Host failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>C: Host network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>D: Local network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>E: Automated customs examination system failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>EDP/Automated Equipment Failure</category>		<number>57</number>		<content><![CDATA[FLIGHT PLANS<br><br>A: Local equipment failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>B: Host failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>C: Host network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>D: Local network failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>E: Communication failure with ATC System<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>F: FMS failure<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>EDP/Automated Equipment Failure</category>		<number>58</number>		<content><![CDATA[OTHER AUTOMATED SYSTEM FORMAT<br><br>A: Failure or breakdown of the handling performer’s inhouse system<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>B: Technical system failure or breakdown<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>C: Failure or breakdown of other suppliers’ systems (catering, fuel etc.)<br><b>Responsible ITEC</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>61</number>		<content><![CDATA[FLIGHT PLAN (LATE COMPLETION OR CHANGE OF FLIGHT DOCUMENTATION)<br><br>B: Late completion/sending of flight dispatch documentation<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>C: Incorrect flight dispatch documents (e.g. incorrect fuel planning)<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>D: Late filling or late updating of ATC flight plan<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>E: Incorrect filling of ATC flight plan<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>F: Change to flight plan after briefing due to operational reasons.<br><i>This code shall apply to the cases, where the flight plan changes due to alternate aerodrome, notam, weather, slot, runway changes, route changes e.g which emerge as a part of the operational needs. However, code 62 shall apply if the change of fuel or load does not lead to a change in the flight plan.</i><br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>G: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>H: Failure in completion of/missing flight kit (jeppsen, take-off, CSPD etc.)<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>I: Missing aircraft documents (MEL, QRH, FCOM e.g.)<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>62</number>		<content><![CDATA[OPERATIONAL REQUIREMENTS (FUEL, LOAD ALTERATION)<br><br>B: Awaiting of final weight (fuel critical flights)<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>D: Alteration to fuel after briefing due to operational reasons.<br><i>This code shall apply to the cases, where the fuel alterations due to alternate aerodrome, notam, weather, slot, runway changes, route changes etc, which emerge as a part of the operational needs. In the case of payload restricted flights, provision of regulated value by the pilot-in-command with respect to the latest weather report – request for an alternate runway, and alteration to fuel due thereto. Request for fuel supply or additional fuel due to long taxiing time.</i><br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>E: Alteration to load after briefing due to operational reasons.<br><i>This code shall apply to the cases, where the load alterations due to alternate aerodrome, notam, weather, slot, runway changes, route changes etc, which emerge as a part of the operational needs. In the case of payload restricted flights, provision of regulated value by the pilot-in-command with respect to the latest weather report – request for an alternate runway, and alteration to payload due thereto.</i><br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>N: Flight operation instructions<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>63</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE CREW BOARDING OR DEPARTURE PROCEDURES (OTHER THAN CONNECTION AND STAND-BY) (FLIGHT DECK OR ENTIRE CREW))<br><br>A: Late boarding of entire crew<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>B: Late boarding of cokpit crew<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>C: Late boarding of entire crew due to the crew transportation vehicle<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>D: Late boarding of cokpit crew due to the crew transportation vehicle<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>E: Late crew pick up (even though the crew transportation vehicle is ready and available)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>F: Airport transportation/Airport access congestion/ closure<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>G: Security procedures (entire crew briefing etc.)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>H: Pre-flight procedures under the responsibility of entire crew <br><i>The delays occurring due to the deficient performance of the procedures to be completed by the entire crew before the flight (failure to affix signature, customs clearance etc.).</i><br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>J: Pre-flight procedures under the responsibility of flight deck crew <br><i>The delays occurring due to the deficient performance of the procedures to be completed by the flight deck crew before the flight (failure to affix signature, customs clearance etc.).</i><br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>64</number>		<content><![CDATA[FLIGHT DECK CREW SHORTAGE (SICKNESS, AWAITING STAND-BY, FLIGHT TIME LIMITATIONS, CREW MEAL, VALID VISA, HEALTH DOCUMENTS ETC.)<br><br>A: Sickness CREW/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>B: Awaiting stand-by crew<br><b>Responsible CRWP</b><br><br>C: Flight time limitations<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>D: Travel documentation<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>E: Crew planning or crew control error<br><b>Responsible CRWP</b><br><br>G: Injury or death<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>H: Insufficient operational rating (CAT 1 - CAT 2 etc.).<br><i>Applicable in the cases, where a higher crew than planned awaits due to the necessities that emerge during the operation. (E.g. The case of an airport, which is normally allowable for operations with a cat1 crew but requires a cat2 or cat3 limit due to the worsening of weather conditions.)</i><br><b>Responsible CRWP</b>/FOPS<br><br>R: Mandatory/ minimum crew resting time<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category></category>		<number>65</number>		<content><![CDATA[FLIGHT DECK CREW SPECIAL REQUEST (NOT WITHIN OPERATIONAL REQUIREMENTS)<br><br>A: Holding by the crew of passenger boarding announcement <br><i>This code shall also apply for the delays in boarding due to ctot in breach of OM PART-A operational procedures.</i><br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>B: Maintenance checks not mentioned in the minimum equipment list<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>C: Late catering request<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>D: Reported technical defects not identified. <br><i>The defect reported by the crew not identified as a consequence of the check by the technical staff. (It was detected that there was no defect.)</i><br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/TECH<br><br>E: Late reporting of technical defect<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>N: Defuelling, additional fuel, flight plan change requests by the flight deck crew (in spite of operations, dispatch approval)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>O: Standby, pass problems of the relatives of the crew members<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>P: Failure to admit passengers in compliance with the sick passenger admission requirements<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>R: Requests by flight deck crew members to leave the flight or for substitution of any flight crew members for personal reasons<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>66</number>		<content><![CDATA[LATE CABIN CREW BOARDING OR DEPARTURE PROCEDURES (OTHER THAN CONNECTION AND STAND-BY)<br><br>A: Late boarding of cabin crew<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>B: Late arriving of cabin crew due to the crew transportation vehicle<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>C: Late crew pick up (even though the crew transportation vehicle is ready and available)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>D: Airport transportation/Airport access congestion/ closure<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>E: Security procedures (cabin crew briefing etc.)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>H: Pre-flight procedures under the responsibility of cabin crew <br><i>The delays occurring due to the deficient performance of the procedures to be completed by the cabin crew before the flight (failure to affix signature, customs clearance etc.).</i><br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>67</number>		<content><![CDATA[CABIN CREW SHORTAGE (SICKNESS, AWAITING STAND-BY, FLIGHT TIME LIMITATIONS, CREW MEALS, VALID VISA, HEALTH DOCUMENTS ETC.)<br><br>A: Sickness<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>B: Awaiting stand-by crew<br><b>Responsible CRWP</b><br><br>C: Flight time limitations<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>D: Travel documentation<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>E: Crew planning or crew control error<br><b>Responsible CRWP</b><br><br>G: Injury or death<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>R: Mandatory/minimum crew resting time<br><b>Responsible CREW</b>/CRWP<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>68</number>		<content><![CDATA[CABIN CREW ERROR OR SPECIAL REQUEST (NOT WITHIN OPERATIONAL REQUIREMENTS)<br><br>A: Inaccurate passenger count<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>B: Inaccurate/late request - catering<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>C: Inaccurate/late request – toilet service<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>D: Inaccurate/late request - cleaning<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>E: Evacuation slide deployed<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>F: Holding/delaying by the crew of passenger boarding announcement<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>G: Security check lasting longer than specified time<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>N: Extra or late request of cabin crew food<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>O: Late request of non-standard supplies (blankets, earphones etc.)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>P: Galley/food check<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>R: Requests by cabin crew members to leave the flight or for substitution of any flight crew members for personal reasons<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>S: Late reporting of technical defect<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Flight Operations and Crewing</category>		<number>69</number>		<content><![CDATA[CAPTAIN’S REQUEST FOR SECURITY CHECK (EXTRAORDINARY)<br><br>A: Captain’s request for security check (extraordinary)<br><b>Responsible CREW</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto<br><b>Uncontrolled</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>71</number>		<content><![CDATA[DEPARTURE STATION<br><br>A: Outside aircraft limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: Outside crew limits (CAT 1 - CAT 2 etc.)<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>R: Weather outside operational limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>X: Slot missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>72</number>		<content><![CDATA[DESTINATION STATION<br><br>A: Outside aircraft limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: Outside crew limits (CAT 1 - CAT 2 etc.)<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>R: Weather conditions outside operational limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>73</number>		<content><![CDATA[EN-ROUTE OR ALTERNATE<br><br>A: Outside aircraft limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: Outside crew limits (CAT 1 - CAT 2 etc.)<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>R: Weather conditions outside operational limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>Z: Outside aircraft limits Due to ATFM regulation<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>Y: Outside crew limits (CAT 1 - CAT 2 etc.)<br><i>Due to ATFM regulation</i><br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>X: ETOPS (aerodromes available for landing with 2 and 4 engines according to A/C type) <br><i>Due to ATFM regulation</i><br><b>Responsible ATFM</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>75</number>		<content><![CDATA[DE-ICING OF AIRCRAFT (REMOVAL OF ICE AND/OR SNOW, FROSTPREVENTATION EXCLUDING UNSERVICEABILITY OF EQUIPMENT)<br><br>A: De-icing/anti-icing on designated remote area<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: De-icing/anti-icing at parking position<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>C: Repetition of de-icing after holdover time exceeded<br>ResponsibleWHTR<br><br>D: Inadequate equipment Inadequacy of existing equipment due to excessive demand<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>E: Equipment failure <br><i>In the case of any equipment breakdown during operation</i><br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><b>Uncontrolled</b><br><br>F: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>G: lack of liquids<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>H: Removal of snow and ice from fan blade<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>76</number>		<content><![CDATA[REMOVAL OF SNOW, ICE, WATER AND SAND FROM AIRPORT<br><br>A: Closure of airport due to severe weather conditions<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: Non-availability of parking positions due to weather conditions<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>C: Removal of snow, ice, water and sand from airport<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Weather</category>		<number>77</number>		<content><![CDATA[GROUND HANDLING IMPAIRED BY THE ADVERSE WEATHER CONDITIONS<br><br>A: Interruption of fuel supply or services<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>B: Apron conditions<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>C: High winds – door operational limits<br><b>Responsible WHTR</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Air Traffic Flow Management</category>		<number>81</number>		<content><![CDATA[ATFM DUE TO ATC EN-ROUTE DEMAND/ CAPACITY (STANDARD DEMAND / CAPACITY PROBLEMS)<br><i>REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE.</i><br><br>Z: ATC routing<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>Y: High demand or capacity<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Air Traffic Flow Management</category>		<number>82</number>		<content><![CDATA[ATFM DUE TO ATC STAFF/ EQUIPMENT EN-ROUTE (REDUCED CAPACITY CAUSED BY INDUSTRIAL ACTION OR STAFF SHORTAGE OR EQUIPMENT FAILURE, EXTRAORDINARY DEMAND DUE TO CAPACITY REDUCTION IN NEIGHBORING AREA)<br><i>REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE.</i><br><br>Z: Industrial actions<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>Y: Equipment failure<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>X: Staff shortage<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>W: Military activity<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>Q: Extraordinary demand due to capacity reduction in neighboring area<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>V: Special events<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Air Traffic Flow Management</category>		<number>83</number>		<content><![CDATA[ATFM DUE TO RESTRICTION AT DESTINATION AIRPORT (AIRPORT AND/OR RUNWAY CLOSED DUE TO OBSTRUCTION, INDUSTRIAL ACTION, STAFF SHORTAGE, POLITICAL UNREST, NOISE ABATEMENT, NIGHT FLIGHTS, SPECIAL FLIGHTS)<br><i>REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE.</i><br><br>Z: High demand/ATC capacity<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>Y: Industrial actions (strike etc.)<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>X: Equipment failures<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>W: Staff shortage<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>V: Accident/Incident<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>U: Military activity<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>T: Special events<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>S: Noise abatement/Night curfew<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>R: Other<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>N: Radar failure<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>O: Closed airport/runway<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b><br><br>L: Political unrest<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Air Traffic Flow Management</category>		<number>84</number>		<content><![CDATA[ATFM DUE TO WEATHER AT DESTINATION<br><i>REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE.</i><br><br>A: ATFM due to weather at destination<br><b>Responsible ATFM</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airport and Governmental Authorities</category>		<number>85</number>		<content><![CDATA[MANDATORY SECURITY<br><br>A: Congestion security checkpoints<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>B: Baggage reconciliation; failure to offloading the baggage of passengers, who do not show up for boarding or who are offloaded after boarding<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>C: Extra/special airport security abandoned articles<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>D: Bomb warning<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>E: Security breach<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>F: Additional/special security inspections<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>G: Mandatory passenger offloading<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>H: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>I: Equipment failure (computer, x-ray equipment failures)<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>N: Late opening of the security office at the final check point before boarding<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>O: Security discords (TAV security – police disputes)<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>P: Special security requirements inside the airport (passenger – baggage – carry-on baggage)<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>Q: Late arrival of aircraft security (private) staff, inadequate number of or errors by staff<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>R: Late arrival of, inadequate number of or errors by aircraft security staff of Turkish Airlines Inc.<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>S: Security search due to suspicious package (on board)<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>T: X-ray scan of baggage at the ramp<br><b>Responsible SECR</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airport and Governmental Authorities</category>		<number>86</number>		<content><![CDATA[IMMIGRATION, CUSTOMS, HEALTH<br><br>A: Immigration (passport)/customs infrastructure system<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>B: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>C: Health.<br><i>Including the delays due to the checks conducted in respect of the epidemic diseases declared by WHO.</i><br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>D: Passenger traveling with improper/invalid/unsatisfactory documents (INAD / DEPORTEE etc.)<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>E: Incoming passenger check<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>F: Aircraft disinfection<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>G: Aircraft customs clearance procedures<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>H: Quarantine<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>J: Congestion on passport check points<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>N: Customs control on internal/ transfer baggage<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>O: Passport computer system failure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>T: Late DEPORTEE / INAD passenger boarding<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airport and Governmental Authorities</category>		<number>87</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRPORT FACILITIES (PARKING STANDS, RAMP CONGESTION, LIGHTING, BUILDINGS, GATE LIMITATIONS ETC.)<br><i>THE REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE IF ATFM REGULATION HAS BEEN ENFORCED.</i><br><br>G: Occurring of any of the following at the destination station <br><i>This code shall apply if the slot message includes GA87 or EA87.</i><br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>H: Late or lack of follow-me for push back <br><i>Excluding the follow-me vehicles of the Company.</i><br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>J: Break down of airport fuel systems<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>K: No push back clearance due to construction<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>L: Ground communication system failure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>M: Insufficient fire cover<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>N: Public address/flight information display system failure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>P: Passenger transport system failure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>R: Electrical system failure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>S: Lack of check-in counters<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>T: Jet bridge inoperative<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>U: No push back clearance due to infrastructure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>V: Baggage sorting system down/slow<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>W: Gate limitations/no gate available<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>X: Lighting and buildings<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>Y: Ramp congestion <br><i>This code shall apply to the cases of such equipment other than those servicing to the Company located in the ramp area, which cause delays in the operations. This code shall also apply to the delays occurring as a consequence of the failure of the related vehicles, equipment and personnel, who and who are to serve, to arrive in time due to ramp congestion.</i><br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>Z: Lack of parking stands<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airport and Governmental Authorities</category>		<number>88</number>		<content><![CDATA[RESTRICTIONS AT DESTINATION AIRPORT (AIRPORT AND/OR RUNWAY CLOSED DUE TO OBSTRUCTION, INDUSTRIAL ACTION, STAFF SHORTAGE, POLITICAL UNREST, NOISE ABATEMENT, NIGHT CURFEW, SPECIAL FLIGHTS)<br><i>THE REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE IF ATFM REGULATION HAS BEEN ENFORCED.</i><br><br>A: Restrictions due to curfew<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>B: Industrial actions (strike etc.)<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>C: Political unrest<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>D: Airport closure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>E: Runway closure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>N: Noise restrictions<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>O: Inadequate number of staff<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>P: Night curfew<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>Q: Special flights (VIP, military, celebration etc.)<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Airport and Governmental Authorities</category>		<number>89</number>		<content><![CDATA[RESTRICTIONS AT AIRPORT OF DEPARTURE WITH OR WITHOUT ATFM RESTRICTIONS (INCLUDING AIR TRAFFIC SERVICES, START-UP AND PUSH BACK, AIRPORT AND/ OR RUNWAY CLOSED DUE TO OBSTRUCTION OR WEATHER,)<br><i>THE REPORTED “REGCAUSE” CODE SHALL BE APPLICABLE IF ATFM REGULATION HAS BEEN ENFORCED.</i><br><br>Z: ATC capacity<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>Y: ATC Industrial action<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>X: ATC staffing<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>W: ATC equipment<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>V: ATC accident/incident<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>U: ATC due to de-icing<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>T: ATC special event<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>S: ATC weather<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>R: ATC restrictions due to curfew <br><i>Such as night flight</i><br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>P: ATC Political unrest<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>N: ATC environmental<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>M: Airport Closure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>L: Runway closure<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>K: Start-up/push-back clearance delay (local ATC)<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>J: Lost flight plan by ATC<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>H: Construction work/maintenance<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b><br><br>G: Other<br><b>Responsible ARPT</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>91</number>		<content><![CDATA[LOAD CONNECTION (AWAITING LOAD FROM ANOTHER FLIGHT)<br><br>N: Awaiting passenger and/or baggage with connection flight<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/GOPS<br><br>O: Awaiting connection cargo or mail<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/GOPS<br><br>P: Short connection (passenger/baggage)<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/GOPS<br><br>R: Awaiting passenger and baggage from a flight, for which our Company acts as the marketing carrier<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/GOPS<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>92</number>		<content><![CDATA[THROUGH CHECK-IN ERROR (PASSENGERS AND BAGGAGE<br><br>A: Failure to conduct through check in – inaccurate transit/transfer passenger and baggage figures<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>B: Missing/incorrect separation of transit/transfer/local loads<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>N: Check-in error – passenger and baggage<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>O: Check-in error – passenger and baggage (unsatisfactory documentation)<br><b>Responsible GOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>93</number>		<content><![CDATA[AIRCRAFT ROTATION (LATE ARRIVAL OF AIRCRAFT FROM ANOTHER FLIGHT)<br><br>Z: Late arrival due to departure delay at the previous station<br><b>Responsible REAC</b><br><br>Y: Late arrival due to en-route delay<br><b>Responsible REAC</b><br><br>X: Late arrival due to delay after landing<br><i>Code 75 shall apply for the delays in arrival related to de-icing.</i><br><b>Responsible REAC</b><br><br>W: Late arrival due to high demand for destination station<br><b>Responsible REAC</b><br><br>V: Late arrival due to weather at destination<br><b>Responsible REAC</b><br><br>U: Late arrival due to technical reasons<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>94</number>		<content><![CDATA[CABIN CREW ROTATION (AWAITING CABIN CREW FROM ANOTHER FLIGHT)<br><br>A: Awaiting operating cabin crew of the flight<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/CRWP<br><br>B: Awaiting positioning or deadhead cabin crew<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/CRWP<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>95</number>		<content><![CDATA[CREW ROTATION (AWAITING CREW FROM ANOTHER FLIGHT (FLIGHT DECK CREW OR ENTIRE CREW))<br><br>A: Awaiting operating entire crew<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/CRWP<br><br>B: Awaiting positioning or deadhead flight deck or entire crew<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/CRWP<br><br>C: Awaiting operating flight deck crew<br><b>Responsible REAC</b>/CRWP<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>96</number>		<content><![CDATA[OPERATIONS CONTROL (RE-ROUTING, DIVERSION, CONSOLIDATION, AIRCRAFT CHANGE FOR REASONS OTHER THAN TECHNICAL)<br><br>A: Re-routing<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>B: Consolidation of flights<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>C: Aircraft/ equipment change – non-technical reasons<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>D: Diversion<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>E: Rescheduled ground time less than declared minimum ground time<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>F: Late dispatch release<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>G: Controller/ planner error<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>H: OCC disruption<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>N: New fuel arrangements due to operational requirements<br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>S: Emergence of secondary causes due to technical breakdown or damage<br><i>One of the codes 46, 51 or 52 shall apply as appropriate solely for the first delay, and code 96S shall apply for all other related changes that occur on the same day. (one day before is inclusive for extended range flights)</i><br><b>Responsible FOPS</b><br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>97</number>		<content><![CDATA[INDUSTRIAL ACTION WITH OWN AIRLINE<br><br>A: Within the local station<br><br>B: Within the entire company<br><br>C: Within passenger services/handling<br><br>D: Within ramp services/handling<br><br>E: Within cargo<br><br>F: Within catering<br><br>G: Within flight deck crew<br><br>H: Within cabin crew<br><br>I: Within technical department<br><br>J: Support units<br><br>K: Within fuel supplier<br><br>L: Other operational activities<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>98</number>		<content><![CDATA[INDUSTRIAL ACTION OUTSIDE OWN AIRLINE (EXCLUDİNG A.T.S.)<br><br>A: National strike<br><br>B: Whole handling company<br><br>C: Passenger services/handling<br><br>D: Ramp services/handling<br><br>E: Cargo<br><br>F: Catering<br><br>G: Technic<br><br>H: Cleaning<br><br>I: Support units<br><br>J: Fuel<br><br>K: Other operational activities<br><br>L: Security<br><br>M: Fire Dpt.<br><br>N: Authorities<br><br>O: Airport<br><br>X: Slot (CTOT) missed due thereto]]></content>	</code>	<code>		<category>Reactionary</category>		<number>99</number>		<content><![CDATA[MISCELLANEOUS (TO BE EXPLAINED IN SI)<br><br>A: Miscellaneous (to be explained in SI) <br><i>This code should be used only when it is clear that a reason cannot be matched to a code above</i><br>]]></content>	</code></annuaire>